-== 字幕制作：石磊 ==-
-== Caption Maker：Stone ==-
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
是谁先发现尸体的？
Who discoveredthe body?
是我
I did
总捕头，他是廖家的总管
Chief, he's the butlerofthe Liao Family
这是你家主人的卧房吗？
Is this the master-bedroom?
不，这是家主人静修之处
No, this is his study
平时家主人是睡在夫人房里
Mymasterusually sleptinthe lady's room
那夫人呢？
Where's the lady?
夫人前天带着少爷、小姐
She leftwiththe young master andyoung miss
回娘家去了
...the daybefore, to visitherparents
那么昨晚上
So yourmaster,
你家主人是一个人在这儿静修了
...was all byhimselflastnight?
是…不是
Yes... um, no
什么？
Begyourpardon?
还有爱奴
Ainuwas there too
来了…
Here they come
请…
Please...
快点
Hurry
Hurryup
快
C'mon quick
快点
Hurry
好了…
Alright...
快点
Hurry
Hurryup
货都到齐了吧
Is everything here?
托春爷的鸿福，一切都很顺利
Yes, the trip went quite smoothly
燕顺子，打开来看看
Openthe boxes, Yan Shunzi
走
Let's go
让开
Move over
走开…
C'mon, beatit...
你们是什么人？
Who are you people?
你们把我抓来干什么？
Why didyou bring me here?
伍华天
Wu Huatian
春姨，这丫头叫爱奴
Lady Chun, this girl's called Ainu
她父亲是个穷教书的
Herfatheris apoorteacher
我们盯了她好几天
We tracked heraroundforafew days,
才把她弄到手
...before we kidnapped her
爱奴？
Ainu, is it?!
这名字倒挺不错的
It's a good name
好烈的性子
God, whatatemper!
这是什么鬼地方？
Whatkind of a godforsaken place is this?
聪明的把我给放了
Allowme to go ifyou're sensible,
不然我报官把你们都给抓起来
Orl'll callthe officials to arrestyou all
这个女孩子，男人一定喜欢
Men're gonna go crazyforthis girl
来人呀，把她们安置好
Come on, settle downthe girls
是，走…
Yes, go
伍华天，跟我去拿银子
Wu Huatian, come with me foryourpayment
请你点一点
Please countit...
春姨的银子还不错嘛
Oh, ltrustyou
没有纰漏吧！
No mistake I suppose!
四季春的名声可不是闹着玩的
Ourbrothel's reputation is important
你放心，我们男人虽然色胆包天
Don'tworry, no matterhowlustfulwe seem
不过我相信我手下
I knowthatnone ofmy staff...
没有一个敢动你春姨的人
would dare to give you anytrouble
可是我嘛…
As formyself...
老毛病还没改呀
You haven't changed abit
还是不喜欢男人
I mean, you still don'tlike men
可惜呀！
Whatapity!
请坐…
Have a seat...
春姨
Lady Chun
这么晚才来
Atthis late an hour!
来人，拿酒来
Come, getme some wine
老板
Boss
怎么样，全检查好了吗？
What's up, done withthe checking?
差不多了
Almost
老板
Boss
怎么样？
Whatis it?
她好凶呀，不绑不行
She's being violent, needs to be tied up
她个性强一点
She's aheadstrong girl
不过倒是上等货呀
But she sure holds a class ofherown
死丫头
You rotten girl!
怎么样，有没有纰漏？
So, anything missing?
有
Yes
这个三天前就叫人开了
This one was defloweredthree days ago
是谁干的？
Who did it?
我不能说
I can'ttell
如果我说了，他就会杀我
He'll kill me, ifl do
是吗？
Is that so?
怎么样，说出来总比活受罪好
Come on, speak out orsuffer
我不说，我不能说
I can'ttell!
我说，我说
Okay, I'lltell
周海
Zhou Hai
你认识她吗？
Do you knowher?
我早就告诉过你们
I've toldyou people before
春姨是惹不得的
Lady Chun isn't one to be messed aroundwith
二婆子
ErPozi
在
Yes madam
这批新货明天就开始训练
Training starts tomorrowforthis lot
二婆子
ErPozi
在
Yeah
多加一点明矾
Add abitmore alumto clearup the water
水淡了，肌肉不够收缩
Wouldwork wonders forthe skin
是
That's right
多加一点明矾
Some more alum here
那个女孩子呢？
Where's that girl?
你是说爱奴？
You're referringto Ainu?
我不吃…
I am not eating...
我不吃，我情愿饿死
I'd ratherstarve to death
我知道这是个鬼地方
I knowthis is hell
你们不是人，是鬼
And allyou, you're nothuman
快放了我
Letme go rightnow
我早说了不容易制服吧
I've toldyou she can'tbe controlled
老妖怪，你听过春姨手下
Have you everheard even once that,
有谁制服不了的吗？
I can't control my own people?
怎么样？
So, what do youthink?
我这个房间不错吧！
Such anice roomthis is!
假如你乖乖听我的话
Lfyou listento me
这个房间和这四个丫头都是你的
You'll have the room andthe maids
你想想看，住在这儿多舒服
Justimagine the comforts ofliving here
爱奴，到那个时候
Atthattime, Ainu
什么大官、财主
Allthe wealthy officers, landlords...
都拜倒在你的石榴裙下
will be mesmerised by you
戴不尽的金银珠宝
You'll have countless jewellery,
享不尽的荣华富贵
Endless wealth and glory
爱奴，你还要什么呢？
What else do youwant?
我什么都不要
I don'twantanything
怎么样？
So?
这个你可以要了吧！
Is this whatyouwant?
不…
No
来人呀！
Is someone there!
在
Yes, madam
先给她一顿鞭子
Thrash herwiththe cane
是
Yes, madam
别打了
That's enough
是
Right
你们都出去
You may go out
是
Okay
好白嫩的皮肤
You've got silky smooth skin
爱奴，何必呢？
Why, Ainu?
你为什么不乖乖的听我的话呢？
Why don'tyou justlistento me?
爱奴，你知道吗？
You knowwhat?
你真是太美了
You're reallybeautiful
我好像有点爱上了你
lthink I mayhave fallenforyou
我不要吃
I don'twantto eat
哑巴哥，你要是真的好心
Please, ifyou are kind
求你帮帮忙，放我出去
Justletme get out ofhere
死哑巴，还不赶快出来
Heymute boy, get out ofthere
请…
This way please
老太爷，您好
Good day, sir
您好久不上这儿来了
Haven't seenyoufora while
老太爷，您好，老太爷
Good day, sir
老太爷
Sir
老太爷，您好
Good morning, sir
老太爷
Sir
当心点
Carefulthere!
搀着老太爷
Give him ahand
老太爷来了
The elderly gentleman is here
老太爷
Good morning, Sir
比我还早
You're earlierthan me
坐…
Be seated please...
春姨，又有什么新鲜的雏儿上来了
Acquired anynewbirdies recently?
他说真是不同凡品
Quite extraordinary accordingto him
可惜只有一个人，我们四个人…
Too bad, there isn't enoughto go around
那当然是老规矩了
Same old rule applies
谁出价最高谁先乐嘛！
The highestbidderwill getto enjoyfirst
当然…
Of course
不过这位姑娘谈头要高一点
Butthis once, bidding price will starthigher
由五百两开始
Startwithfive hundred, shall I say
五百两？
Five hundred?
那那个妞儿一定…
She mustbe a...
放开我
Letme go
包虎
Bao Hu
好
Yes
四位老爷，请开吧
Let's startthe bidding, gentlemen
一千五百两
One thousandfive hundred
全县的米都是你老兄一手包办
You own allthe rice inthis county...
一千五百两出得太少了吧
that's alow offercomingfromyou
是…
Yeah...
还是我开吧
Myturn
三千两，是吧
Three thousand
横霸三省的总镖头，真豪气
Nowthat's quite an offer!
我倒忘了我写了多少
Lforgothowmuch I put down
让我来给你们看看
Letme showyou
五千两
Five thousand
是的…
Yes, yes
怎么样？
Well?
老太爷，你就这样认输了吗？
Have you given up, old master?
谁说的，我还没开呢
Who said so? I haven'tmade mybidyet
老太爷，怎么你一个钱都不出？
You didn'twrite down an amount
谁说我不出？
Says who?
我儿子是这儿的知府大人
My son is the local governor
难道我花钱还要写银票吗？
I don'tthink I needto write a cheque
我花钱从来都是用嘴说的
ljust open mymouth when spending
我嘛，出五千一百两
Five thousand one hundred
五千一百两
姜到底是老的辣
Can neverunderestimate the elderly
又是老太爷独占花魁
Andwe have a winner
看起来你们三位只好迟一步了
You gentlemen willtake yourturns later
- 王师爷  - 在
- Wang  - Yes, Sir
明天到银库去拿五千一百两银子来
Withdrawthe moneytomorrow
接着就接爱奴到长春阁去
Then we'll come and pick Ainu up
是
Yes, sir
放开我
Let go
叫你放开我
I said, letme go
把这个碗里的万人迷给她
Feedthis bowl of sedatives to her
好…
Alright...
放开我…
Letme go
老爷
Master
快…出去…
Quick, get out ofhere
怎么回事？
What's going on?
爱奴…
Ainu
醒了…
She's awake...
让开
Move away
在四季春，要死也没有那么容易
ltisn't easyto take yourown life here
来人
Someone
在
Yes
把她给我押回黑房去
Lock herup inthe dark house
是
Right
哑巴哥哥
Brothermute
你何苦救我？
Why didyou save me?
我早晚都要死
I am goingto die soonerorlater
不，人不应该死的
No, you shouldn'tkillyourself
你不是哑的
You can speak!
以前我不说话
I didn't speak a word...
是我自己不想说
because I refusedto
我恨透了天下所有的人
I hated everyone
为什么？
Why?
我从前是黑道中人
Lwas involved in illegal activities
后来…
Later...
我爱上了一个大户人家的千金小姐
lfell in love with arich girl
她父亲知道了我是黑道中人之后
Herfatherfound outaboutme...
当然反对这头婚事
and he was against ourmarriage
为了拆散我们，他暗算我
He setup aplotand parted us
废了我一半的武功
Afterthatattack I can hardlyfight
那个女孩子自杀了
Later, the girl killed herself
因为她的正人君子父亲
Because herso-called respectable father...
把她给强奸了
raped her
你说我该不该恨天下所有的人
So canyou understand whylturned cynical?
那你为什么对我那么好？
How come you're so goodto me?
因为…
Because...
你长得有点像那位小姐
You beara slightresemblance to that girl
不过…你不要误会
But, don'tworry
我绝不是爱上了你
I am notin love withyou
我只是同情你
Whatl have, is sympathy
看到你受了人家的委屈
Forthe waytheytreatyou.
不该逃避，不该自杀
You shouldn'tkillyourself
我们要报复
We'll retaliate
四季春从来没有一个姑娘
Withoutmy permission...
能走得出去
no girl has walked out ofthis door
快走
Go
燕顺子，你的武功早已废了一大半
Yan Shunzi, you are no matchforme
你这不是找死吗？
Are youtryingto getkilled?
走
Go
燕大哥
Brother Yan...
还想动
See ifyou can move now
燕大哥…
Brother Yan...
燕大哥，你不能死，燕大哥
Please don't die
爱奴姑娘
Miss Ainu
你…你不能死
You... you can't die!
你死了，谁给我报仇？
Lfyou die, who'lltake revenge forme?
燕大哥…
Brother Yan...
那你不用报仇，可以死了吧
You can die now
燕大哥
Brother Yan...
燕大哥，你不能死，你不要死
Please don't die, please don't!
燕大哥，你不能死，燕大哥
Brother, you can't die!
你不要死
Don't die on me!
燕大哥…
Brother Yan...
怎么样？
So whatnow?
要死我马上给你个痛快
Lwill killyou ifyou so desire
要活就得依我
Oryou'll listento me ifyouwishto live on
好，我依你
Alright, I'll do as you say
是谁最先发现尸体？
Who foundthe body?
是我
I did
总捕头，他是廖家的总管
Chief, he's the butlerofthe Liao Family
这儿是你家主人的卧房？
Is this the masterbedroom?
不，这是家主人静修之处
No, this is his study
平时家主人是睡在夫人房里
MyMasterusually sleptinthe lady's room
那夫人呢？
Where's the lady?
夫人前天带着少爷、小姐
She leftwiththe young master andyoung miss
回娘家去了
the daybefore, to visitherparents
那么昨晚上
So yourmaster...
你家主人是一个人在这儿静修了
was all byhimselflastnight?
是…不是
Yes... No
什么？
What?
还有爱奴
Ainuwas there too
爱奴？
Ainu?
姑娘，有人要找你
There's someone here to see you, Miss
爱奴姑娘，这位是新来的季捕头
Miss Ainu, ChiefJi, recently appointed
他说有事要见你
He wants to see you
你们出去
You all please go out
是
Yes
季大人，你找到这儿来
ChiefJi, I am amazedto see you here
雅兴倒不浅呀！
This is a surprise!
不，我是为公事而来
No, I am here on business
那一定是很要紧的事了
Then itmustbe important, I guess
我是想来问问姑娘
I'd like to ask you
你昨晚上是不是到过廖员外的家里
Were you atLiao's house lastnight?
衙门什么时候连我们这种事
Since when didthe brothel...
都管起来了呢？
fall underyourjurisdiction?
不，不是衙门要管你们的事
No, itisn'taboutthe brothel
是因为昨天晚上廖员外给人害死了
You see, Liao was murdered lastnight
他们家里的人说
His servants saidthat,
你是最后见到廖员外的人
Youwere the lastpersonto see him
依你说，是我害死他的？
Are you inferringthatl killed him?
我也不敢这么说
No, I dare not
不过据他家里的人说
Butaccordingto his servants
你离开他家的时候是子夜时分
...you leftaround midnight
而我们依积雪的厚度断定
And his time of death was around midnight...
他死的时候也是子夜时分
based onthe accumulation of snow
那你们看出他死在我走前
Then, did he die before I left...
还是在我走了之后呢？
orwas itafterwards?
这一个…
That...
很简单嘛！
It's so simple!
如果你能够证明他死在我走之前
Lfyou can prove thathe died before I left
那么我一定是凶手
Then I mustbe the murderer
现在就可以抓我回去
You may arrestme rightnow.
如果你不能够证明
Lfyou have gotno proof,
那我就告诉你
Then letme tellyou
我走之前他还没有死
He was still alive when I left
他是死在我走了之后的
He must've died afterlwas gone
你怎么能够证明你走之前
How couldyou prove that...
他还没有死呢？
he was still alive whenyou left?
那你又怎么能够证明
Then how canyou prove that
我走之前他已经死了呢？
...he diedwhile lwas stillthere?
季大人
ChiefJi
你初到此地大概有所不知吧
I guess you are newintown
廖国强为富不仁，刻薄成家
Liao Guoqiangwas amiser...
好色好酒
an alcoholic and a sex-addict
其实他早就该死了
He oughtto have been dead ages ago
你还找什么凶手呢？
Why do you care forhis death?
好了，季大人
Alright, ChiefJi
还有什么事要问吗？
Anything else?
如果没有
Lfnot, please leave
我有点累，倒想休息一下，请吧
I'd like to restnow
再见
See you
大人，您走了？
Chief, you're leaving?
刚才的事，你看到了没有？
Didyou see that?
爱奴昨天晚上杀了廖员外
Ainu killed Liao lastnight
今天官差来查案
Andthe officers are here
什么？
What?
春姨，你这样纵容爱奴
Lady Chun, you shouldn't spoil her
又教了她一身武功
You eventaughtherkungfu
我看四季春十年的基业
lthink ourbusiness oftenyears...
迟早会毁在她手里
will be jeopardized byherone day
你…
You...
你别忘了
Don'tforget
十年前你为了喜欢女人诱拐少女
You kidnapped ayoung girltenyears ago...
被西南五省的武林人士围剿
andyouwere attackedfrom all sides
逼得你走投无路
You had nowhere to go
要不是我包虎杀退他们
Had itnotbeenforme
救了你一命
to save yourlife,
你会有今天吗？
...do youthink you'd be here now?
十年来我为你退出武林
I leftthe martial arts world behind
帮你开了这间妓院
And opened up this brothelforyou
做出这种丢尽祖宗面子的事
This is disgraceful enoughforme
你还不知足？
Aren'tyou satisfied?
这是你心甘情愿的
Youwere willingto help
春姨，这是因为我爱你
That's because I love you
真可惜，我就是不喜欢男人
Too bad, I am notinterested in men
爱情就是那么奇怪
Love is strange indeed!
你爱我，我却喜欢爱奴
You love me, butl like Ainu
可是爱奴如今杀人了
Ainu killed someone
现在是廖国强
ltwas Liao Guoqiangthis time
跟着就是卓文坚、李长安
Zhuo Wenjian, LiZhangan will be next
最后可能就是你跟我
Then itwill be ourturn
为什么？
Why?
你…
You...
我是试试你的武功
I am justtestingyourskills
看我能否制得住你
And making sure ifl'm still in control
因为包虎在担心
Bao Hu is worriedthat...
有一天你会杀了我们的
youwill kill us one day
你为什么要把廖国强杀了？
Why didyou kill Liao Guoqiang?
没什么
Forno particularreason
大概我像你一样，开始恨男人
lthink I'm becoming like you, hating men
所以我也要向他们报复
That's whyl seek revenge
也可能我会变成更爱你
This could meanthatl'll love you more
不喜欢别的男人爱我
And I don'tyearnforthe affection ofmen
那…你第一次看到血腥味
Then, were you excited...
痛不痛快？
whenyoufirsthad ataste ofblood?
够刺激
Verymuch so!
不过也像外面的雪一样
Butit's similarto the snow outside
没什么味道
Totallytasteless!
爱奴
Ainu
将来你真的会杀我吗？
Do you intendto kill us inthe future?
怎么会呢？
Of course not
我跟你现在是一个人了
Withyou, it's like we're one in being
你死了，我还能活得成吗？
I can'tlive withoutyou
爱奴
Ainu
哥俩好，七个七个巧
One frogjumped overthe pond... plop
三星照，不回手，枪到了
Two frogs jumped over, jumped overplop
我喝…
I drink
老李，怎么样？
Li, what's going on?
哥俩好，好一对
One frogjumped overthe pond plop
不回手
Two frogs jumped over, jumped over
你如果真怀疑爱奴干的话
lfyou do suspectAinu
把她捉回来，怎么样？
then how aboutwe arresther?
对，我去捉
Alright, I'll go
不…我去…
No, I'll
别胡闹
Enough nonsense
总捕头是新派人，当然是新作风了
The chiefmusthave his newworking style
不过话又说回来了
Butthen,
爱奴的靠山硬，咱们碰不得
Ainu has strong patronage, we can'ttouch her
你们知不知道爱奴的出身？
Do you knowherhistory?
婊子没什么出身
Whores have no history
不是自己想卖就是家里人逼她卖
They're eitherforced orhave volunteered
反正都是一样
It's the same story
不过听说她与众不同
The word is she's quite outstanding
那倒是真的
That's true
尤其是她的床上功夫
Especiallyin bed
你试过？
Have youtried it?
我哪配
I can'taffordto
爱奴来往的都是王公大人
Ainu serves the rich andthe famous
小的有几两骨头？
I am justa smallfry
还有…
Besides...
爱奴专挑男人却不许男人挑她
Ainu herself selects herclients
无论你花了多少银子
No matterhowrichyou are...
她都当你是个屁
She gives a damn!
那么她挑的是什么人？
Whatkind of clients does she prefer?
刚才不是说过了嘛
As ljustmentioned
除了刚死的廖员外
Apartfromthe dead Liao
有这个福气的只有卓老爷跟魏大人
Zhuo Wenjian and masterWei
周总管，爱奴姑娘来了
Mr. Zhou, Miss Ainu is here
爱奴姑娘，您来了
Hello, Miss Ainu
请
This way please
你在外面等我吧
Please waitforme here
是
Okay
请
Please
这边
This way please
老爷，爱奴姑娘来了
Master, Miss Ainu is here
来…
Come...
请
Please
进来
Do come in
请
Please
进来…
Come in
走…
Leave...
你们干什么？…
Whatare you doing?
你们干什么？
魏大人，我们是来救你的
MasterWei, we're here to save you
救我？他妈的
Save me? Bullshit
来人呀…
Is somebodyhere...
你没事吧
Are you alright, Sir?
你是什么人？
Who mightyou be?
小人是府衙捕头季德
Ji De, chiefpolice officer
去你妈的
Go to hell
老爷，你怎么了？
What's going on, master?
他是什么人？
Who is he?
他就是府衙的总捕头
Chiefpolice officer
刚才还在门外求见
He's askingforyou outside
小的特来相救
I am here to rescue you
你来救我？
Rescue me?
小的来迟，大人受惊
Sorryl am late
滚，你给我滚…
Get out ofhere
马上给我滚
Out! Now
你要是滚迟半步
Rightnow, orl'll complain...
明天我递帖子给府差大人把你严办
to yoursupervisortomorrow
- 滚…  - 我…
- Get out  - I...
滚
Out!
周总管，你们老爷到底怎么回事？
Mr. Zhou, what's withyourmaster?
我们老爷早年专捡雏儿硬上弓
He's abitworn outfrom
掏坏了身体
his experimenting allthese years
现在他要给女人硬上弓才济事
He only gets turned on bybondage now
他跟爱奴就是玩这一套嘛
That's whatit's all about
总捕头老爷，你现在该明白了吧
Nowyou should understand, chief
我请喝酒，走
Letme buy you a drink, come on
喝酒，走
C'mon, drink up
爱奴，来呀，快来吧
Ainu, come on
爱奴
Ainu
来呀！
Come on
怎么了你？
What's withyou?
快来呀，我要你
Come on, lwantyou
你要什么？
What do youwant?
快点给我做
It's you I desire
魏建忠
WeiJianzhong
你还记得你第一次糟蹋我的时候
I rememberthe firsttime
就是这样把我绑在床上的吗？
Youtied me up in bed...
从那个时候起，我就发誓
Fromthat day on I swore
有一天我也要把你一样的绑起来
...lwilltie you up one day
弄死
And killyou
现在机会总算来了
The time has come
倒在你的身上
It's yourturn now
捕头老爷，你又想干什么呀？
Chief, whatis it?
我总觉得有点不对劲
I'm stillworried
不能进去，捕头老爷
You can't go in, chief
你看灯都黑了
The lights are off
你看，你还好意思进去
See, youwouldn'treallywantto intrude
不要嘛，你坏死了
Don't, you bad boy!
天，老爷真行
The master's still gotit
爱奴一直叫呢
Ainu is moaning!
床都响了，还不快走？
Justleave
走呀…走了
C'mon, get going
魏建忠，你没想到会有这一天吧
You neverthought ofthis day, didyou?
爱奴姑娘，你走了？
Miss Ainu, you're leaving?
季捕头，你还没有走呀？
You're still here, ChiefJi
一定是不放心
You mustbe worried
所以在这儿等我出来，是不是？
That's why youwaitedforme here, isn'tit?
不过，你最好还是进去看看
You bettergo check inside
否则他要是真的死了的话
Orelse youwouldn'tknow...
你还不知道呢！
ifhe's really dead
起驾
Let's go
总捕头，你又要干什么？
What do youwant?
我想进去看看你们老爷
Lwantto go inside
这个时候老爷正在休息呢！
He's asleep rightnow
你要是进去的话，那不是有点…
You putme in a difficult spot
总捕头，我看今天晚上
lthinktonight,
她一定不敢动手
She wouldn't dare
不好了…着火了
Oh, no! Fire!
着火了…
Fire!
救火…快点救火
Hurry! Putit out!
爱奴
Ainu
捕头大爷…
Chief
季捕头，有什么事吗？
ChiefJi, how can I help you?
你昨天晚上放火烧死魏大人
You setthe fire to kill masterWei lastnight
我现在来捉你
I am here to arrestyou
放火？谁看见了？
Setafire? Anywitnesses?
我走的时候房子好像还没有着火吧
Sure wasn'tanyfire when I left
是你刚走了以后
Butjustafteryou left
房子就烧起来了
The whole house was inflames
那一定是我走了以后
Then itmust've been someone else...
有人进去放火
who setthe fire afterl left
我没看见别人进去过
I didn't see anyone going in
那你看到我放火啦？
Didyou see me startthe fire?
即使你杀人不留痕迹
Eventhoughyou didn'tleave atrace
今天我非抓你回去不可
I'll have to arrestyoutoday
季捕头，别说你没有证据
ChiefJi, not only you've no evidence...
证明是爱奴杀人
to prove thatl amthe murderer
就是你亲眼看见了
Even ifyou've seen me
也应该先查一查
You should've done yourhomework
四季春是谁的地方
Do you knowwho owns this place?
如果你真的要把爱奴怎么样
Lfyou reallywantto arrestme
也应该先问问知府大人的老太爷
You should askthe governor's dadfirst
谁？
Who is it?
好快的剑
Good swordplay
原来是你
So itwas you!
你拜候了我两遍
You've visited me twice
礼尚往来
Justreturningthe favour
我也应该回拜你一次吧
This is myturn
是不是要告诉我谁是凶手？
Do youwantto tell me who's the murderer?
不，正好相反
No, onthe contrary
我是来劝你，别再管此事
I am here to ask youto step away
你凭什么要我不管？
Why?
那你又凭什么要管呢？
Whynot?
凭它
I'm backed bythis
把剑放下
Put downthe sword
现在大概你不管了吧
Nowyouwill step away, won'tyou?
你坦白的告诉我
Tell me
为什么三番四次的不让我管这件事
Why do youtryto stop me?
我是为你好
It's foryourown sake
否则，后悔的是你
Otherwise, you'll be sorry
如果我一定要管呢？
Whatiflwon'tlisten?
也好，我告诉你
Fine, I'lltellyou
下一个死的是卓文坚
Zhuo Wenjian will be the next
什么？混账
What? Nonsense!
你说爱奴要杀我？
Ainuwants to kill me?
简直胡说八道
That's rubbish
太老爷，她是认真的
Master, she means itforreal
真…真个屁
Can'tbe
你简直狗咬耗子多管闲事
You've gottoo muchtime onyourhand
你什么事不好管，管到我头上来了
Nowyou're interfering
你是不是当捕头当腻了
Are you sick ofbeing an officer?
小的不敢
No, sir
不过廖员外、魏大人他们都先后…
ButMr. Liao and Mr. Wei...
这…这有什么稀奇嘛！
What's so strange aboutthat?
人总是要死的
We all have to die sometime
你怎么可以把帐算在爱奴的身上
You can'thold Ainu responsible
可是
However,
太老爷为什么不可以少见爱奴一面
lfyou don't see Ainu
以策万全呢？
...youwill be safer
怎么，卓老爷，是不是不要我了？
MasterZhuo, you don'twantme anymore?
爱奴，宝贝
Ainu honey
爱奴，我的宝贝，谁说我不要见你
Mybaby, of course not
我宁愿死也不能够不见你
I'd ratherdie than not seeingyou
我的心肝宝贝，宝贝儿
Mylittle baby
过来
Come over
是
Yes
怎么了？季捕头，你也来凑热闹呀
ChiefJi, youwantto jointhe fun?
卓老爷，原来这玩意
MasterZhuo
你们两个男人也可以一起玩的？
Do youwanthimto join us?
谁说我要跟他一起玩？
Of course not
快滚
Get out
太老爷
Old master
滚，马上给我滚
Get outnow
是
Right
这儿没有你们的事，出去…
Get out
小狗子，去把几个姑娘带进来
Go bringthe girls in
是…
Yes...
来…快点进来
Hurry
这三个是干什么？
Whatare these three doing here?
你整天说要玩新花样
You always say youwannatrynew stuff
所以今天我给你一个大四喜
Lemme give youthe fourwinds today
大四喜？
The fourwinds?!
四季春的
Yes, it's the brothel's special
你…你为什么还不脱？
Why aren'tyoutakingyourclothes off?
我呀，我是北风
I amthe north wind
如果要我，那得看你行不行了
lfyouwantme, then it's up to you
快拿酒来，快…
Come getme the wine
怎么样，卓老爷
MasterZhuo
我看今天还是休息吧
Perhaps it's time foryouto rest
谁说的？我现在才是西风
What? I am only onthe westwindyet
发生什么事了？
Whathappened?
- 撞门  - 是
- Knock it down  - Sure
怎么回事？…
What's going on?
不要动
Don'tmove
- 来人  - 是
- Men  - Yes
马上请府台大人
Getthe governor
是
Yes
老爷…
Master...
爹…
Father...
这回你跑不了
You can'trunthis time
- 上铐  - 是
- Cuffs  - Here
慢
Wait
季捕头，马上把爱奴姑娘给我放了
ChiefJi, lethergo
大人，她就是凶手
She's the murderer, sir
我叫你马上把爱奴姑娘放了
I said, lethergo rightnow
你听见了没有
Didn'tyourhearme?
是
Yes, sir
爱奴姑娘，我送你回去吧
Allowme to take you home, Miss Ainu
这件事还得请你多包涵包涵
And I apologize forthis incident
季捕头，今天晚上的事
ChiefJi, aboutwhathappened here
你千万别对外人提起
You can'tletanyone know
为什么？
Whynot?
因为太老爷
Because the old master...
是自己服食春药过多致死
died of an aphrodisiac overdose
这事有关府台大人的清誉
The governor's reputation is at stake
所以你千万不能叫外人知道才好
So you had betternottell anyone
男人都是一样
All men are the same
宁愿死也要我们女人
They all lustafterus
眼看他们一个个断气
I have watchedthem die one afteranother
心里面实在痛快得很
I am ecstatic with joy
廖国强、魏建忠、卓文坚
Liao Guoqiang, WeiJiangzhong, Zhuo Wenjian,
还有一个
...and one more
李长安
LiZhangan
听说他也押镖回来
Heard he's returnedfrom his job
怎么，卓老爷他们三个都死了？
What? They all died?
是的
Yes
听说从前你们四个人常在一块儿
I heardyou spentalot oftime together
所以我特别来通知你
That's whylwantto warnyou
要提防爱奴
Beware of Ainu
爱奴能够杀他们，是他们不懂武功
They allweren't versed in Kung Fu
碰到了我可没那么容易
Butl'll be atough nutto crack
来人呀
Someone there
是
Yes
今天晚上把爱奴接到我这儿来
BringAinu here tonight
是
Right
李大爷，爱奴姑娘来了
MasterLi, Miss Ainu's here
你来了
There you are
他们…
They...
他们是在你还没有动手杀我之前
Theywill killyou...
先杀了你
before youtryto kill me
如果你真的要杀我
lfyou reallywantto kill me
你一个人还不够吗？
lthink you can do itall by yourself
你们出去
You all mayleave
走
Go
你为什么弄死他们三个人？
Why didyou killthe otherthree?
为了单爱你一个人
So thatl may save mylove foryou
你们男人真是不识抬举
You men just don'tappreciate
如果我真的要杀你
lflwantto killyou...
为什么我不带武器呢？
where's the weapon?
来呀，你搜搜看
Come on, search me
你搜呀！
Come on
Go ahead!
我是要你搜搜看有没有带武器
I'll indeed search if ornot you've a weapon
又不是要你抱我
Then again, I didn'task youto hug me
怎么样，是不是在你杀我之前
Well, youwanna sleep with me...
再风流一次？
one lasttime before you kill me?
你急什么呀？
What's the hurry?
等我把衣服全都给脱光了
Letme strip first
你再看看我有没有带武器
Thenyou'll know,
再来也不迟呀
if ornotl'm carrying a weapon
爱奴已经来了吗？
Is Ainu here?
来了，在里面呢
Yes, she's inside
什么事？
What?
我想进去
Lwantto go inside
这门是我们家主人特制的
This is a special door
只有从里边开
It can onlybe openedfrom inside
外边是不能开的
Notfromthe outside
你这个淫贼，真该死
You deserve to die
明知道我是来杀你的
You knewl am here to killyou
可是你还是逃不过色欲这一关
But stillyou lustafterme
你…
You...
来人呀，救命…
Somebody, please help
撞门
Knock it open
你也该有今天
You deserve this
你再也想不到
Nevercouldyou have thoughtthat
你造了这么一个房子
this very special roomyou built...
专门来糟蹋女人
to abuse and ravage women
结果你也就死在这儿
Andyou'll end up dying here!
你还记不记得
Do you remember...
你第一次就在这儿
the firsttime in here...
用这条鞭子打我
whenyouwhipped me?
除了这扇门，还有没有别的通道？
Is there no wayin, exceptforthis door?
除了那扇门，没有别的通道
It's justthis door, no otherway
撞，用力撞
Come on
你们走开，我来
Make way you guys, I'm coming
进去…
Go on in
他已经死了
He's already dead
季捕头，你是个好差官
ChiefJi, you're a good officer
可惜你捉错人了
Butyou've caughtthe wrong person
追…
Afterher...
上…
Move
住手
Hold it
季捕头，两年以前
ChiefJi, two years back
我就是像这些女孩子一样
lwas like them
在别的地方给他们硬抢过来的
Gotkidnappedfrom otherplaces
他们把我卖给春姨
They sold me to Lady Chun
求生不得，求死不能
ltwas aliving hell!
逼着被男人糟蹋
Lwas coerced into prostitution
我杀了几个男人
I killed afewmen
我杀死他们
I killedthem...
只不过是为了报仇
onlyforrevenge
你如果要抓真正的凶手
lfyou're lookingforthe real culprits
就把他们抓起来
Arrestthem
臭婊子
Bitch
春姨…不得了啦
Lady Chun, we've gotaproblem
什么事？
Whatis it?
不得了啦，爱奴出卖了我们
Ainu plotted againstus
他们在城门口出了事
They gotintercepted atthe gate
那，爱奴怎么样？
Whathappenedto Ainu?
她倒机灵，先走了
She turned out smart, andfled
我还以为她受了伤
lthought she must've been hurt
春姨，我早就告诉过你
Didn'tltellyou earlier!
四季春迟早会毁在那个贱人手里
The brothelwill be ruined by Ainu
干什么？
What?
我要去宰了她
I am goingto kill her!
四季春没有了
The brothel is finished
我们可以到别的地方去从新再来
We could startanew ata differentplace
没有了爱奴，我可活不了
butl can'tlive withouther
你真是色迷心窍
You've been blinded bylust
爱奴存心害我们，你还不醒悟
Ainu didthis forrevenge
也许她会害了你，她可不会害我
She won'thurtme, never
因为我跟她是一个人
Because she and I, we're one
- 放  - 走
- Come on  - Go
春姨，难道你真的为了这个贱人
Willyoufightagainstus...
跟我们全体兄弟动手
forher?
我也不知道
I am not sure
不过我告诉你
Butletme tellyou
有我在，谁也不能动爱奴
No one harms Ainuwhen I'm here
上
Kill
Attack
吓死人了
This is scary
这是钥匙，放走后院的姐妹
Here's the key, letthe girls go
快走…
Hurry...
快起来…
Come on
快走…快逃走…
Run... run away
快走…
Hurryup
Getaway...
快…快点出去
Quick... leave fast
包老板…
Mr. Bao
什么事？
Whatis it?
不得了，爱奴把后院的姑娘
Ainu setthe girls free
全部都给放走了
All ofthem
你听到了没有？
Didn'tyou hearwhatl said?
我早说过
I've said itbefore
有我在，谁也不能动爱奴
No one harms Ainu as long as I'm here
难道你现在还看不出
Can'tyou see that...
爱奴在向我们报复
this is herrevenge?
你信吗？
Do you believe that?
怎么会，我们两个是一个人
No way, she and I are the same person
春姨
Lady Chun
看样子我们两个应该来个了断
We should settle this once andforall
现在就找死，不早一点了吗？
Youwantto die already?
你的鸳鸯鬼手
Youryinyang ghosthands aren't powerful enough
也不比我的寒心刀厉害多少
...formy spine-chilling sword
包虎，何必呢？
Why? Bao Hu?
就是你拼掉了性命
It's notworth it
我们两个人还是在一起
We will still be together
我看不一定吧
I ain'treally sure
你这种女人根本是不值得爱的
The likes ofyou don't deserve mylove
可是我后悔得太迟了
Butit's too late forme
爱奴，你不会因为我残废了
Ainu, youwouldn't stop loving me...
你就变心吧？
nowthatl am handicapped?
不会的，我不会变心的
No, lwon't
因为我从来也没有爱过你
Because I've neverlovedyou
现在我正在看
Looks like this is it
今天大概可以报仇了吧
Todayis the time forrevenge
本来我想用恨来报复
lwantedto use hate forvengeance
结果我失败了
Butlfailed
后来我想到一个更好的方法
Hit on abetterplan instead
是天底下从来也没有人用过的
thinking, no one else would've used it
那就是用爱来报仇
I used love to take myrevenge
我用爱杀死了廖国强
I killed Liao Guoqiang, WeiJianzhong
魏建忠、李长安、卓文坚
LiZhangan, Zhuo Wenjian bylove
为了四季春
To bringthe brothel down
我离间你跟包虎，我也用爱
I used love to come betweenyou and Bao Hu
真没想到，爱比恨更毒辣
Never'd imagine the damage love could cause
你…
You...
想不到你比我还狠毒
Didn't expectyou to be more vicious than me
不要骂我
Stop it!
我和你一样的卑鄙下流
We are both despicable,
冷酷、无情、残忍、病态
heartless, merciless, cruel and sick
现在你总该知道
Nowperhaps you'd have a glimpse of...
你自己是多么的令人讨厌了吧
howrepulsive you are!
你不用下手了
You don'tneedto!
反正我活不了啦
I am dying anyway
这大概是天生的冤孽吧
I guess this is karma
虽然你杀死了我
Eventhoughyou've killed me...
可是我…我一点都没有恨你
Yetl don'thate you abit
爱奴
Ainu
我…我爱你
I... I love you
你能够在我死之前
Couldyou kiss me once more...
吻我一次吗？
before I die?
这是我最后一次要求
It's mylastrequest
可怜可怜我吧
Have pity on me
谢谢你，爱奴
Thank you, Ainu
谢谢你陪我一起到鬼门关
Thank youfordyingwith me
我早已在口里装了一颗毒药
I had apoisonous pill in mymouth
刚才你吻我的时候
lwas chewing it...
我已咬破它
whenyou kissed me
你还不像我
You are unlike me
你还有一点良心
You've still gotyourconscience
还有一点爱
And alittle love
爱奴
Ainu
Ainu!
爱奴，我来晚了…
I amtoo late, Ainu
爱…
Oh, Ainu...